9 a.m.
in Shanghai.
Shenzhen is here in Hong kong.
You're watching the China show.
I'm Yvonne Man with David Ingles.
Good morning.
We're counting down to the open the
markets here in Hong kong.
Let's get to your top stories today.
Oil prices are holding on to these
gains.
Early gains, stocks slipping after this
flare up in violence in the Gulf,
putting this four week ceasefire between
the U.S.
and Iran in jeopardy.
Secretary of State Scott Basin calls for
China and other nations to join in
guiding ships through the Strait of
Hormuz, even as the US claims total
control of the vital waterway.
President Trump, meanwhile, signals his
meeting next week with Xi Jinping is
pushing ahead despite rising tensions
over Iran and also Taiwan and Philippine
inflation data set to show the impact of
higher energy prices.
The central bank expects the highest
print in three years, adding more
pressure on the region's worst
performing currency.
Well, we are, of course, waiting.
Of course, the key central bank
decisions coming out of Australia here
today.
We have Philippine's inflation coming
through.
The energy shock, of course, of this
part of the world is going to be the key
thing to focus on when it comes to
central banks coming at a time now when
we are talking about the U.S.
and Iran exchanging fire once again.
Yeah, I mean, the fundamental story is
changing.
The RBA is going to tell us that we're,
I think, expecting a hike there.
This Philippine inflation, which Yvonne
just mentioned as well.
This is an extremely let me just caveat
this diplomatically, an extremely ugly
number.
7.2%.
The estimates four, four, five and a
half percent were coming off 4.1, so
almost doubling from 4.1%, which was
already on the high side of things for
March at 7.2%.
This will likely let me just mention, is
to judging on the language and the tone
coming through out of the central bank.
In a conversation with the BSP about two
weeks ago.
This should actually push them even more
so, if not already, towards another rate
hike as well.
7.2% is the highest inflation rate going
back to 2023.
Keep in mind, at the start of the year,
we were sub two on headline inflation
there.
We now have a seven handle on this.
It's unsurprising why borrowing on the
Philippine peso has been the weakest
weakest performer across our fixed here
at the Asia Pacific.
Given the sensitivity of course where
these oil importing nations really have
on really what goes on the volatility
around oil prices.
Right.
When you talk about Brent now being back
above 110 or so, you know, once again,
we are seeing renewed attacks.
You know, it seems like Project Freedom,
this whole plan to escort vessels
through the Strait of Hormuz has
actually led to the reigniting of more
tension.
So certainly that's one thing that
really to contend with here today in
central bank, certainly after the Fed
last week now sounding a little bit less
dovish.
It will be interesting to see what the
RBA RBA says because they're set to hike
it a third straight time.
But you got to wonder if they going to
start taming that.
The hawkish sort of tilt here now just
given now there is some concerns about
growth too of their potentially.
Yeah there's a fine balance right.
At some point you will be hiking into a
perceived slowdown and I think when the
Aussie dollar has been already on the
high and the strong side of things, it
is one of the best performing
currencies.
So we'll see really what the RBA says
around that conversation that
out-of-province out to be in this bond
space in really, really, really bad day
we had in the bond markets yesterday.
I think we're back about 4.4% on the US
ten year.
We don't have, of course cash treasuries
trading today, but suffice to say the 30
year yield also took quite a milestone
there.
And as far as US rates are concerned,
equity markets, though, are risk off.
Yeah, although it's not a full, full
roster, we have to be here in the
region.
Yeah.
I mean when you have Hong Kong sorry,
China, Korea as well as Japan all closed
here today.
So that air trade taking a bit of a step
back and really just taking a pause here
today.
So you're not going to get that sort of
all those tailwinds into this equity
market here today.
Maybe that's perhaps why you're seeing
when it comes to A50 futures, we're
still in negative territory here.
It is relatively risk off today with
Taiwan V not that exception.
You take a look at how the markets
opening up here.
We're still up about a third of 1%.
So bucking most of the trend here today,
just given the latest headlines when it
comes to Iran.
But certainly we'll see how things fare
when Philippines opens up in just half
an hour.
Given that pretty ugly print, as you
mentioned, with inflation.
Yeah, lots to watch out for today.
Let's get to more details on the latest
overnight in Iran and why oil prices are
114 again.
Let's bring in our team a lot of pens.
Our deputy managing editor here and set
china correspondent min below with some
of the other analysts.
Well, let me start with you.
What happened and who started it?
Well, that's that's a great question.
Well, what we see is is a flare up of
hostilities in the in the Middle East.
There were some attacks by Iran on some
U.S.
assets also in the UAE, which is the
closest U.S.
ally in the Gulf region.
Of course, the U.S.
retaliated, fended off some attacks from
what the president called some small
boats and swift boats.
And this happened while the U.S.
was attempting to escort some ships
through the strait.
So what we have now is a bit of a flare
up.
We don't know yet if this will lead to a
full scale escalation or whether this is
a blip on the radar.
Both sides are saying that they're still
talking.
Nobody is declaring the ceasefire as
having collapsed yet.
So there's still some hope that this can
be contained
in the scheme of things.
This was a relatively small scale
incident, but that just shows the risk
that we continue to run while this cease
fire is on.
Talk about the diplomacy that we might
see now that things have flared up
again.
Yeah, I mean, President Trump did say
that he is looking ahead, looking
forward to this meeting with President
Trump.
President Trump is looking forward to
the meeting with President Xi next week.
So it looks like all signs are pointing
to that summit still happening.
Not going to be good.
A second time, at least from the US
side.
Last week we did see those phone calls
as well between Foreign Minister Wang Yi
and the Secretary of State, Marco Rubio.
There was a separate phone call with a
Twitter representatives as well between
Holly Fung and Scott Bessant.
So yes, it looks like that is still
happening.
And of course, with the Iran overhang,
the latest escalation has been those US
sanctions on these Chinese refineries
and how China has responded by calling
on its companies not to abide by these
sanctions.
And that is the first time that they are
applying these so-called anti foreign
sanctions law, which China introduced
back in 2021, first time that they are
applying now to push back against what
they see as long arm jurisdiction.
And yes, President Trump's got better.
And actually, I think China to
participate in helping to escort these
ships out of the Strait of Hormuz.
China hasn't done it before.
They are not likely to do it again.
Now, they're also calling on the U.S.
is also calling on the South Koreans to
join in this.
What do we know about that?
Yeah, so President Trump singled out
South Korea because their ship got shot
by Iran.
And President Trump saying that that
ship was not escort it.
And so is high time South Korea to join
in that mission.
But again, so far, there hasn't been
takers
for us calls to join in those efforts.
And the South Korean defense minister
has previously said that sending a
warship to the Iran the Gulf region, to
escort those ships, that would require
parliamentary approval.
So it's not something that would be
taken lightly.
And same thing for China.
They have also said that they want
diplomatic and they are not likely to
send a ship that they would see as a
potential escalatory move, especially
when Iran has already resumed attacks
overnight and has threatened that any
U.S.
ships approaching the Strait of Hormuz
to try to escort ships out those ships
could be attacked.
Project Freedom Blog was supposed to
begin yesterday.
Do we know what's going on there now?
Well,
it's a it's it's an interesting
situation there.
I think what happened overnight just
shows the fragility of the situation
when we take it in its totality.
This is the issue with ceasefires.
Until there's a negotiated political
solution to this issue, these sorts of
flare ups might happen at any time and
both sides might use that leverage to
advance their positions in the political
negotiations.
So until there is a solution, until the
two sides move closer politically, this
might this is likely to to to happen
again.
Speaking of vessels being hit, a allies
and I think Vindman mentioned the South
Korean vessel here.
There was a report that Iran had struck
a US naval vessel.
What do we know about that in that?
My understanding is the Americans have
denied that.
That's right.
The most recent news out of the US was
that they denied that report.
Okay.
Thank you.
Oblige Pence, our deputy managing
editor.
Also our thanks to China correspondent
below on the latest when it comes to the
Iran front.
Still ahead, we're talking things
through markets and what this means now
that we have seen.
Now bond markets certainly are waking up
to the reality of higher for longer from
the Fed.
Also with this new renewed sort of
threat to oil prices here today, equity
markets continue to take things in
stride in some ways apart from today.
We'll look at how developments the
Middle East could play out across Asian
markets with Mark Franklin from Manulife
Investment Management, Asia Multi
Passive Head.
And now they opened up trade in Hong
Kong.
This is the China show.
Welcome back.
So just to recap the breaking
inflation print, a really, really,
really bad one coming out of the
Philippines above every single forecast.
It had a seven handle.
7.2%.
We're coming off a 4.1% in March.
It's hard to imagine this was about 2%,
I believe, at the start of this year.
And hence the peso is one of the worst
performing currencies globally.
Oil, as you can see at 114, does not
help that case, of course, for net
importers.
And the assessment coming through,
coming through from Bloomberg Economics
has given their reaction to what
happened yesterday was that it just
underscores how fragile the cease fire
remains and that their base case will
remain.
A and this is out of that.
Glasser and her team here.
All of this underscores that despite a
change of leadership we had for a
prolonged conflict, protracted conflict
with ongoing and sporadic fighting will
keep oil prices elevated.
Yeah.
Let's bring in Mark Franklin now, Asia,
head of Multiasset Solutions that made
you life investment management.
So we're seeing tensions in the Middle
East once again flare up again.
I mean, you're seeing stocks continue to
ride on earnings and the like, but you
talk about bonds.
You're starting to see that melt up in
yields.
Once again, oil continues to rate
elevated.
How do you actually look at multi assets
now and what's the strategy going
forward?
Yeah, there's a ton of drivers in
markets.
I suppose what we've got to try to do is
focus on what the cyclical impacts are
and what the structural impacts are from
what's going on.
And the cyclical impacts are inevitably
high oil prices.
Energy linked plays should do well.
Those depend on energy as inputs will
struggle.
And then there's also the activity
implications Because of the supply
shock, it's not just a price shock.
So in that sense, which economies, which
regions around the world are more
sensitive to that supply shock?
And that's why we're bifurcating with a
preference more towards the US over
places like Europe.
And then within the equity market
construct, we like those structural
plays like tech and A.I., which still
seem to have good tailwinds and the
energy related plays as well.
How how much does do these recent
headlines reset?
I mean, the last three weeks and the war
affect invest your investment decisions.
I just wonder how how much they still
feature in just your your thinking at
this point.
That's a great question.
One of the things that we're grappling
with at the moment is we can form a
thesis on how the macro will unfold and
build a narrative around that, but
you're only getting rewarded or punished
by price action.
And so we try to stay as closely focused
on what the market's actually doing
rather than what people are saying in
and around them.
That being said, though, you know, we
have been in an environment where
sentiment and flows have driven markets.
Every once in a while.
Fundamentals of macro do reassert
themselves.
And the longer this conflict goes on,
then we will have to start to reassess
the way that we place on the different
pillars sentiment flow, fundamental
macro.
And I think the bond market is certainly
sending some alarm signals here.
When you talk about what we just saw
with Philippines, with that pretty
punchy number of when it comes to
inflation, the RBA said to hike the Fed
last week seemed to show a little bit
less willingness to cut and we're seeing
the possibility of rate cuts were now
being priced out essentially.
Are we likely to see that actually be,
you know, rate hikes being priced in?
It's a good question.
If you look at where the curves that now
it's pricing in about one third to one
half of the hike between now the end of
next year.
So it's very much in the balance.
If you look at the progression of data,
both in terms of growth and inflation,
US growth oriented data has held up
quite well and inflation is grinding
higher.
So the Fed was well within its rights to
try to create to a policy flexibility,
at least in its communication.
But of course, what the bond market will
do is probably move ahead of Fed
communication and effectively the Fed
will either endorse or challenge market
pricing.
I think where we're at now is the data
is somewhat in the balance.
We got jobs data from Friday.
You're probably likely to see an ongoing
moderation, the pace of hiring, but the
steady state of hiring activity that's
required to sustain the unemployment
rate where it is now has clearly come
down.
So that's to some extent may be a
possibility.
The market looks through that will
continue to remain focused on inflation.
And any early signs of activity in the
US context is starting to show
sensitivity because so far it hasn't.
But obviously in other regions,
particularly Europe and emerging
markets, it has started to do so.
The what is the appropriate exposure?
You're not a fixed income with the all
in yields that we have at the moment,
especially in the Treasury market where,
you know, we're pushing four and a half
percent on the ten year.
Yep.
So there's a curfew and there's also an
interim fixed income view.
I think on a curfew, we continue to
remain a bit more comfortable playing
around the belly in the front ends of
the curve and not taking too much term
premium risk.
That being said, though, if rate pricing
does start to shift to the other side,
you could see a bear flatness.
So we're starting to neutralise those
curfews at the margin somewhat.
And then the second point into fixed
income, we like inflation linked bonds.
That gives you a degree of
diversification.
Should rate pricing start to move higher
again?
Are people asking you about that?
We had a guest yesterday that said,
look, it seems like most investors or
their clients.
Or just willing to kind of see this as
all transitory.
But are they asking for more tips or
inflation linked sort of products?
Not directly, but they're certainly
asking the question on what constitutes
an appropriate strategic allocation in
this kind of macroeconomic regime.
You know, the traditional 60, 40, the
sixties worked okay so long as you've
picked your spots in equity markets, But
the 40 has obviously struggled.
Yeah.
And in that context, maybe a, you know,
a mix of commodities and sort of
traditional fixed income gives you the
requisite diversification and the
portfolio resilience that you require in
this environment.
Will the air trade ever be affected by
what what's going on?
Because so far it has proved more than
resilient in the face of this.
Well, one of the things that will
ultimately scupper the move is whether
you start to see a supply response to
the supply tightness in memory chip
semiconductors more broadly, because
what you're seeing is very aggressive
inventory build and front loading of
demand because of the fear that supply
will be constrained for the foreseeable
future.
Now, if there is a supply response by
the major memory companies in the next 6
to 12 months, then that pricing will
start to unravel and the need to
frontload inventory build will start to
wither away as well.
So that's really the main driver.
It's more of a fundamental story, but
for the time being, we don't see
evidence of that yet because I think
Samsung reported earnings last week and
they gave somewhat of guidance around
their supply and towards the end of this
year.
How quickly does that information land
on their laps?
Do we see that coming or is that almost
on an earnings report basis?
What I would say is that the market
tends to spend a lot of time looking at
channel checks and identify these
inflection points before the companies
actually report.
So when you start to see memory seats
leading the equity market higher and
start to underperform both in rising and
falling market days, then that will be a
sign that maybe at the very margin,
sentiment is starting to top out.
How do you look at the rotation right
now and how do you chase it?
You know, it's a good question.
So the question is you don't chase
anything blindly at this point.
You had a 50% plus move in a single
month.
But at the same time, you're looking for
plays, which might actually be, I think,
a second order derivative.
So those businesses that are, say, fully
resourced in terms of chip inventory and
we'll start to see tailwinds for
margins.
And then the second point as well as
which tech companies that are buyers of
chips have pricing power to pass on
those rising costs.
So take Apple as an example.
Earnings are quite robust, Margins are
actually expanded.
They signaled that cost pressures were
rising, but that they would have the
ability or at least the intent to pass
that on through higher pricing.
And so when you've got very strong
brands in the tech supply chain, their
ability to absorb that cost shock is is
more resilient than for other companies.
What about energy and how much is
energy?
And I play as it is a geopolitical,
strategic or tactical opportunity.
Yeah, it's a bit of both.
Clearly, in the short term, you've got
this supply shock and this is why it's
very interesting to look at us energy
plays because actually there's an
abundance onshore of crude, whether it's
coming from the gas complex or from the
liquids complex.
And that means that the refiners in the
US are benefiting from rising refinery
spreads globally but are sourcing their
feedstock with a bit of a discount to
global refiners.
So so they're taking share both in terms
of volume and in terms of profit.
So there's a cyclical benefit short term
from the supply and the price shock
longer term as well.
There are undoubtedly structural factors
that are driving energy demand, whether
it's datacentre proliferation and so on.
But one of the structural implications
potentially of what's going on at the
moment, the Strait of Hormuz, is if this
leads to a permanent change in oil
supply dynamics, more and more
governments are going to have to look
for other means to secure energy
resilience.
And so things like nuclear power, you're
seeing more and more governments around
the world sign up to pledges to expand
their nuclear footprint.
And that's why commodities like uranium
actually look quite interesting on a
longer term view.
Should this disruption last more than a
few weeks or does gold stand then?
Oh, yes, I'm going to happen.
Gold Yeah.
Existential question when it comes to
gold keeps coming up.
Yeah.
I mean I think we're in a process now in
the near term of two things.
One is digestion of the gains that we
saw over the last two years is seeing
profit taking.
And then the second thing as well is in
a situation where traditional oil
exporting economies are struggling to
export oil and generate dollars, they're
having to source told us through other
means to keep their dollar reserves in
place, which means reducing their gold
reserves to fund that gold so that US
dollar shortage.
So in the short term, you're seeing some
central banks lighting up their gold
reserves in order to raise dollars.
And so that means that the gold is in a
profit taking phase at the moment.
But longer term as well, structurally we
think that the reasons why gold deserves
the place perhaps more strategically in
portfolios is ongoing.
Fiscal exuberance not going to change
anytime soon.
We're seeing fiscal deficits super high
outside of recession.
It's not normally the case normally in
recessions when fiscal deficits balloon.
And also at some point, central banks
will resume their easing path to respond
to a growth shock.
Mark Fantastic.
We covered everything.
Not China, but we can do that next time.
Mark Franklin Thanks so much, sir.
Asia head of Multiasset Solutions at
Manulife Invest.
Management, mainly China, Japan, South
Korea are shut today.
Hong Kong, of course, is open and the
early going suggests we are going to get
marginal decline 6/10 of 1% to the
downside.
China is at six offshore.
684 is where you are on the exchange
rate.
The opening bell 8 minutes away.
This is the China show.
All right.
Here's your agenda here today.
We're tracking, of course, of the risk
off moves across equities here this
morning.
And mainland markets still remain shut
for another day.
So certainly it's just the Hong Kong
exposure there.
But earnings to tell you about.
We got HSBC, Budweiser brewing that
we're reporting today.
We just got those API numbers from
Budweiser.
First quarter net income did meet
estimates as well.
We talked about those GDP numbers coming
out.
Paul Chan certainly talked them up
leading up to it today.
So we'll see if we in fact see growth at
the five year highs that they're
expecting.
And we got a debut here, Star sports
medicine coming up to an extreme.
Yes, 1609 HK We're up 200% in the early
goings.
This one was massively oversubscribed.
So you split the name and you look at
the latter part.
So it's actually manufactures medical
devices, things like joint surgical
instruments and grinding heads
effectively thinks if you open up your
knee, this is probably what the surgeon
is going to ask for, apart from
scalping, of course.
Speaking of scalping and opening up the
index at this point, 6/10 of 1%.
The downside in the Hang Seng index, a
couple of stocks we're tracking going
into the going into the open today, as
we were pointing out, of course,
earnings right to HSBC.
We talked about that Budweiser brewing
already out with some numbers coming
through as well.
Budweiser a pack out with some numbers.
Flattered that we have anything else
here.
Data, that's a good one there with
Morgan Stanley raising it to overweight.
This is the shares.
So they're saying, you know, the growth
visibility is there.
So expecting this next generation
technologies for sodium ion batteries,
condensed batteries to scale rapidly,
they say here.
So that could drive growth acceleration
for the next three years for them.
So we're up nearly 3% for the stock in
Hong Kong this morning as we talk about.
Right.
It is that renewables it's east those
are some things are really renamed the
whole battery sort of trade there And
there you go.
Big day for star sports medicine.
Yeah, they could be the star 192% on
their debut.
Not as good as some of the others we've
seen recently.
But, you know.
Yeah, you can't have it all.
Take it on a risk off day.
Yeah.
All right.
As we go into the open today, a reminder
that a lot of big markets are shut
across the region.
So mainland markets, a shot.
No stock connect.
Not that that was an Asian as far as
volumes yesterday were concerned.
We're coming off a very strong rally in
tech on Monday, melt up in yields
overnight.
Hence we're getting the risk aversion
here in screens ever so slightly today.
The opening bell 3 minutes away.
This is the China show.
Welcome back.
You're watching the China show.
Mainland markets are shut today.
Futures are pointing lower, though.
A near $0.56 a 1% in rain is also coming
down quite heavily here in Hong Kong.
We have GDP numbers coming out.
HSBC is coming out with earnings today.
So stay tuned for that.
But two and a half hours from now, yeah,
could be a pretty interesting one just
given that this the stock has been up
some 15% year to date and certainly has
been a favorite for a lot of the retail
side of things.
So certainly we'll see what they say
when it comes to the rates outlook, the
Iran impact in the like with HSBC, as
you mentioned, we could be seeing, you
know, it's gloomy out there, but the GDP
print from Hong Kong could be pretty
rosy for the first quarter as well.
Here's how Hong Kong is shaping up here
at the open.
And of course, we talked about here
against this backdrop of a flaring up of
tensions between the U.S.
and Iran.
Once again, oil is elevated once again,
we're back above 113 for Brent.
So that certainly is going to be the big
headwind when it comes to risk assets.
And you're seeing that when it comes to
equities here that melt up in yields
that we saw in treasuries as well, that
is weighing on the equity complex here
today as well.
So you are seeing tech on offer.
HS tech is down close to 1% after what
was a pretty good start to May for the
trading month for just check.
There was that bit of a catch up story,
but we're not seeing that here today
with the exception of Baidu, which seems
to be bucking the trend against most of
the large cap tech here with Baidu up
some 1%.
But Alibaba ten said May one shall be
seeing more than 1% losses there.
HSBC ahead, those earnings as well is
lower.
Keep in mind, though, we're not seeing
that much volumes here because you have
China of Japan, South Korea, you know,
the latter two being the really big sort
of darling sort of markets there are
shut on this Tuesday.
So that certainly could be one thing to
watch and contend with 63 when it comes
to the Chinese currency as well.
You take a look When it comes to
Seattle, though, that seems to be a
standout here, according to Morgan
Stanley.
So you continue to see Bulls kind of
surround the stock here.
They raised the stock to overweight,
just given the visibility that they're
seeing around growth, they say for the
next three years.
We talk about the pipeline and what
you're seeing when it comes to east
sodium ion batteries and the like.
There you go.
And so the stock is up once again, more
than two and a half percent.
And then we have a listing debut to tell
you about, too, as well.
So we talked about health care products
firm.
This is star Sports Medicine.
There you go.
190% gains at the open.
Yeah, it makes things like bone
grinders.
Oh, there we go.
And that's something that you'd hope to
encounter under.
Well, you're under I guess this is a
good way, right?
Inflation coming through earlier on out
of the Philippines, 7.2%.
Quite a nasty number.
You know the the pricing anyway was for
an already hawkish central bank.
So something to watch Some of the big
movers, not so much reaction in the
equity markets.
Let's have a look at the currency and
where we are here, too.
They look 61 I believe is where we are
in the exchange rate.
The hike, the last time they signaled a
hike was possible and I would imagine
this inflation print even cemented even
further.
The next meeting is on the 18th of June.
Now, this is a question this is not a
speculative question.
This is not a speculation is an off
cycle moves possible given, of course,
how we put that question to the central
bank recently.
And they said no,
and I guess we will we will leave it at
that point.
Yeah, but they were still pretty
flexible when it comes to, you know,
hiking multiple times from the governor
their last few weeks or so.
Also with us is Mark Franklin from
Manulife Investment Management here.
We haven't talked about China.
It seems people are not talking about
China, given the fact that you're seen
Japan, Korea, Taiwan be so hot.
Do you think that's warranted?
It's a great question.
Maybe it creates an opportunity for Hong
Kong, China to be a creeping
outperformer in the months to come,
particularly as those very strong
momentum oriented markets might see some
profit taking at some point.
If you look at the growth data that's
come through in China, year to date,
it's been fine, albeit led by net
exports, which may face some headwinds
later on this year's results of global
growth moderating.
But also export markets starting to
challenge China's heavy supply via
non-tariff and tariff barriers.
But absent that, China also, by the way,
has an inflation point, which is not
problematic compared to a number of
other economies.
And whilst fiscal deficits are widening,
they're widening at a relatively modest
pace.
So China principally still does have the
ability to stimulate, although the
appetite to do so thus far has been
quite limited.
It seems to tick all the boxes of a
market that one should own in this kind
of environment.
I wonder why it's not reacting that
well, at least on an overall index
level.
Yeah, I mean, we talk about barbell
approaches where you want some exposure
to high momentum exposures in markets,
but also some positions in your
portfolio which have strong fundamental
resonance either by valuations or by
sort of underpriced opportunity.
So I think Hong Kong, China definitely
falls into the bucket of a valuation
point, which is somewhat attractive.
I think the reason why it hasn't
necessarily been fully catalyzed by the
things that have done so well in the
market series and to some extent you've
got the legacy economy stocks, whether
it's the bank.
So whether it's the the mining companies
or the the coal companies which have
struggled somewhat more.
And therefore, you've got to pick your
points within the market.
But I think more broadly speaking, if we
go through a period of volatility in a
global equity market context, again,
that valuation profile stands out as
being reasonably attractive, a
reasonable risk reward as a starting
point in the household.
Tech names that everyone used to buy up,
they're not quite really benefiting from
this whole A.I.
boom in some ways, right?
Because of the exposure to software and
the concerns of air disruptions there.
And you have these smaller companies
that perhaps foreign investors might not
have that much education or due
diligence on.
I mean, is there still a bit of a gap
you think about the knowledge of some of
these companies or some of these sort of
hardware plays in China?
Yeah, definitely.
I think that, you know, traditional
institutional investors are typically
stuck to the index weights.
It's those investors which have, let's
say, more of a freewheeling approach to
the market where they're looking for
those hidden gems.
But at the same time, we're in an
environment now where you've got to be
careful about managing liquidity risk.
And so you're probably still likely to
see an emphasis on the large cap plays,
the big index weights.
And there, if you look at the gaming
companies, the e-commerce companies,
there are some tentative signs that the
growth cycle has been really
accelerating, albeit for very sector
specific reasons, and that's why the
forward valuations are coming down
somewhat because the growth outlook is
faster this year than it was over the
last couple of years.
If if one sticks to index heavyweights
though, you'd miss a rally.
Yeah.
Are you tempted at all to look beyond,
you know, further down to market cap,
look onshore, for example, or is what
you know, what what what seems to be the
gap right now in terms of information?
Well, one of the things that we've
identified it's been quite interesting
is the Asia A-share premium discounts.
It actually places the mainland market
as being somewhat attractive.
But of course what you have to do is
also manage a currency risk as well.
And given that the yen is weakening
quite considerably before the
intervention last week, you know, the
PBOC and the other authorities are
looking at the CNY and making sure that
it remains competitive in a regional
context as well.
So by going down the roots of
maintenance stocks, you're taking some
currency risk, albeit with relatively
low velocity.
Okay, We're going to leave it there, but
thank you so much.
Stay with us.
Mark Franklin, their head of Multi-Asset
Solutions for Asia at Manulife
Investment Management.
Okay.
For a closer look really at the Chinese
markets and we alluded to this as well,
right?
Some of the big winners in the greater
Chinese markets recently have been on
the Chinext index.
You know, we talked about Seattle there.
Of course, that's the eight shares
granted the Morgan Stanley call.
But it's really this new cohort of new
tech.
Right.
In fact, is this now your new tech index
that people should be looking at away
from and taking a step back from the
Hang Seng tech index, which has has
lagged substantially.
Joining us here on set to talk us
through everything that we just touched
on, here is Marvin Chen, our senior
equity strategist, is here with us to
talk us through this.
So is it Marvin, We talked about this,
right?
Taiwan, Korea, Japan have been doing
substantially well.
China has missed out.
So do we need to be looking at that
dissonance between the two there?
Yeah, I mean, as you mentioned, you
know, the major indices for China have
really lacked this tech hardware
component and this layer of AI build.
You know, these include chips, memory
infrastructure, which includes, you
know, storage and energy.
And these are not very well represented
in major China indices such as MSCI
China and the Hang Seng Tech.
So, yeah, we're still looking at
declines year to date.
But as you mentioned, if we look towards
the CHINEXT index, this index is sitting
at all time highs currently.
Right.
And it does have a lot of these hardware
names.
So, yeah, investors do need to do a take
a little deeper look beyond the index
towards the A-share market and some of
the smaller caps to find some of these
tech hardware plays.
And they're just not as prominent as in
Korea and Taiwan.
Talking about Korea.
Valuations are still around the single
digits when it comes to PE.
So do you think these these stocks are
still cheap?
Yeah.
What's interesting about Korea is even
though the market's up like 60% year to
date, valuations have actually declined
because the earnings outlook has just
been growing faster, much faster than
index.
And
you know this.
So to us, it's been a purely earnings
driven
rally and we would not read too much
into the valuations because, you know,
historically the memory sector has been
very cyclical.
Now, the good news is that, you know, we
are in a supercycle and as long as
earnings momentum continues, we think
that the stocks can continue to have
momentum.
But if there are any signs of an
earnings slowdown, we think valuations
can normalize quite quickly.
And the other thing to note about this
is that, you know, overall, the
valuations have been anchored by just a
few of the tech giants such as Samsung
Electronics and SK Hynix.
If we look at the median p e for the
Korean tech sector, it's actually at
more than half of the tech sector is
trading at more than 33 times forward
earnings.
And this is more in line with kind of
the global.
Averages.
That's an important distinction to look
beyond just that the to the to
the to.
Speaking of to Alibaba Tencent are
reporting I think almost I think on the
same day, if I'm not mistaken next week
the 13th.
Any specific catalyst that they they
could give us.
Yeah I mean I think it could be the
earnings results could be a catalyst
either way.
Right.
It depends on the numbers and the
guidance.
But we think investors will focus on a
few key areas.
One is be you know, is the is the cloud
revenue growth and demand for
infrastructure justifying the
investments.
And also, you know, what their strategy
is going to be to monetize their their
investments.
And, you know, we could see some
divergence in strategy here.
You know we saw that in the in the US
with media and some of the max seven the
divergence in reactions and I think it
comes down to whether you're you know
you're selling the picks and shovels or
you're buying the picks and shovels.
So I think that's going to be a
distinction that investors will want to
kind of identify.
And secondly, obviously, is that is
there any recovery in the core business
is is trying to consumption recovery.
Marvin, great to have you.
Marvin Chen.
There are Bloomberg Intelligence senior
equity strategist there as we look at,
of course, earnings and tech, China and
Korea as well here.
Look at how Hong Kong markets are doing,
of course, as we get into this
commercial break.
And we are continuing to see a downside
risk here when it comes to equities.
And the Hang Seng is now seeing a pretty
deep losses.
There are more than 1% for the Hang Seng
eight shares as well, with HS tech
leading the way lower.
We're down close to 2% for the tech
space here today.
This is Bloomberg.
So major corporate headlines are falling
for you today.
The Trump administration is reportedly
considering an executive order to create
a working group on AI.
The New York Times reports a proposal
could introduce government reviews of
new AI models that resemble a framework
followed in the.
The report says White House officials
briefed executives of anthropic, Google
and Openai last week on some of the
plans under consideration.
Bloomberg has been told that Openai and
Anthropic are both joining and forming
joint ventures with financial firms to
accelerate adoption of their AI tools.
Openai has raised more than $4 billion
from TPG, Brookfield, Advent and Bain
Capital.
Meanwhile, anthropic is partnering with
firms including Blackstone and Goldman
Sachs.
Boosting adoption rates has become
critical for the two firms as they
target IPOs.
And Palantir Technologies has raised its
revenue outlook for the year to almost
$7.7 billion, far exceeding analysts
estimates.
Sales in the first quarter rose to a
record .63 billion, but U.S.
commercial sales fell short of
estimates.
Palantir's long running deals with the
U.S.
and foreign governments now faces
growing competition from rival tech
companies.
Speaking of earnings, HSBC is the big
one today.
Here in Hong Kong, we're down about
1.6%, 141 bucks a pop here, down about
two and a half.
Hong Kong dollars here, a couple of
hours out with some numbers, just 2
hours and 15, give or take here.
So a couple of things, right?
What the exposure is, the Middle East,
how they're affected, how they could
also be benefiting from that.
Let's bring in our finance reporter,
Didi SWE is here with us on set to give
us a preview of what to expect from this
set of numbers.
Yeah, So basically Iran war, we're going
to see what they're going to see around
that and if they're going to be any
charges.
Stanchart last week posted 190 million.
That's right.
Management overlay related to the Middle
East conflict.
So we could see we're likely to see
something similar.
As you know, HSBC looks to take some
precautionary provisions against their
exposures.
You know, it's worth noting HSBC is one
of the, you know, Europe's largest bank
with the largest exposures along with
STANCHART.
Yeah.
So, yeah, that's something to watch
when, you know, HSBC being such a big
trade finance bank, it's also worth
seeing what they see around their
customers, any stress they're seeing in
the exposures in terms of capital
returns.
What can we expect in terms of that?
Well, they expect it forecast to post a
ten cent dividend.
In terms of buybacks.
It's probably unlikely we'll see any
buybacks this quarter because, you know,
they made the big Hang Seng acquisition
loss this year and they said it would
suspend buybacks for a few quarters.
So I think on that front, we're likely
to not see that this quarter.
Okay.
Anything else that we're looking at in
terms of I think generally the banks,
you know, that the pre-tax profits
expected to be flat above 9.6 billion,
but well, we expect to do well.
Stanchart last week also did strong
wealth performance.
Yeah, UBS, strong net, new money out of
Asia.
So we expect to see similar story for
HSBC.
Also on the trading book, it be
interesting to see how they fare because
we've seen Wall Street banks do really
well.
It's been a bonanza.
Equities trading.
I mean, HSBC is an East platform is
probably not as big as these banks, but
it would be interesting to see how they
perform on that front.
Okay.
Thank you.
We there our finance reporter on what to
expect when it comes to HSBC results
coming out in just a few hours or so.
Of course, the first two survivors.
You can also turn to your terminal for
more on those earnings.
T live go is your function for the
latest updates plus commentary analysis
from our expert editors.
This is Bloomberg.
In the world news this morning.
Indian Prime Minister Narendra modi is
BJP has won a historic landslide in West
Bengal state, ending 15 years of rule by
Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee.
And the other scores of BJP is
broadening the support base beyond
traditional strongholds in the north and
west.
The victory gives Modi fresh momentum to
advance his political and economic
agenda.
How does President liking does left the
southern African kingdom of SWAT TV
after a surprise visit that defied
Beijing's efforts to block his
diplomatic outreach?
A source says Lai was returning to
Taiwan on the as Whitney Monarch's
private plane and earlier planned to
visit Taiwan's only African ally was
blocked after three China friendly
nations closed their airspace to his
aircraft.
New evidence is adding to the case that
a Chinese Eastern Airlines plane that
crashed in 2022, killing all 132 people
on board was intentionally brought down.
The US NTSB says fuel switches were
turned off while the Boeing 737 was at a
cruising altitude.
The agency's report was written in 2022,
but only released this month under the
Freedom of Information Act.
Chinese authorities have cited national
security reasons for not releasing a
final report.
Apollo Management says private credit is
now the safer place for investors to be,
even as the rise of artificial
intelligence is dramatically shifting
the investing ecosystem.
The co-president, John Zito, spoke to us
at the Milken Institute Global
Conference about how valuation
frameworks need to adapt to the new
regime.
We're in a completely different regime
for investing.
for how things are going to be over the
next three or four or five years.
If you believe in A.I., if you are in
fact agi pilled,
then you
know that the way that you're going to
have to invest, the way that you're
going to have to underwrite the way that
your entire business is going to have to
function, will have to shift.
And the valuation framework for both
public market investors and private
market investors is going to have to
change.
And that's, I think, very exciting.
I think it's very exciting for people in
the industry who are adaptive and love
investing and love thing around the
corner.
It is it is such a big difference
though, because it used to be an
industry that loved asset light high
margins.
This requires kind of the opposite of
that.
So much investing needs to go into that.
Is this an industry prepared for it
besides, you know, giants, the Apollo is
the blackstones of the world.
I mean, look, look at Intel, for
example.
You know, Intel for like ten, 15 years
effectively was a drag on the entire
equity market.
And for a decade they were viewed as the
the the dumb money for actually
investing in their infrastructure.
And we financed the deal where we
finance the deal two years ago to
finance their fab and to build new chips
in Ireland.
Everybody hated it.
Everyone called us.
And what could you possibly do to invest
in Intel?
And we got refinanced this year.
And the story's not about us getting
refinanced.
It's about the stock this year, which
was up 500% because the entire world
realising that instead of wanting to be
asset light, maybe it's about being
asset heavy.
Maybe what before was the rubric for
success.
It was all about code was the scars
asset.
Right now it's compute, it's data
integrity, data data quality, it's your
talent.
What kind of talent you have.
It's it's all of these things, the whole
framework is, is shifting I think.
And again, I think it's really exciting,
but it's not about private or public.
It's the valuation rubric and how you
think about where you want to be in the
in the strategic ecosystem of your
business.
So the valuation rubric has changed.
Does the industry as a whole realize
that, John, do you think everybody is
going to start to have to change their
mindset in this way, or is it just a
select few that can participate?
I mean, look at look at what we've been
doing.
I mean, I said we're going much closer
to the asset.
We bought Atlantic Aviation this year.
We financed over 0 Billion of Chips
for for Space X, so GPU financings,
power, defense, all of the things that
are going to require to grow all the
CapEx needs and to go asset heavy is
actually the exciting part of private
credit, not the old LBO loans that
people made and everyone talks about the
actual excitement is investment grade
lending for all this CapEx for a lot
more asset heaviness.
The opponent, co-president there, John
Zito with, of course, our colleague
Danny Berger at the Milken Global
Conference in Beverly Hills.
But back to this part of the world, one
of the big releases today was this
really nasty inflation print that came
through out in the Philippines.
And it's 7.2%, really the highest since
2023.
The stats bureau already commenting that
the risk here is really as it pertains
to food inflation that goes into
transport costs and really one of the
most exposed economies to really the
global oil.
The price, which, by the way, right.
We search back to about 115 a barrel
overnight.
So the story, it ain't over yet.
A long shot, Bloomberg Economics.
They've come out with a report in
reaction to the CPI surge and they're
saying this does flag potentially more
rate hikes from the BSP.
And their next meeting is June 18th.
The only question, according to Mara
Henderson, is by how much are they going
to hike now, just given that, as you
mentioned there, we were talking about a
4% print in March, which was already
past their range.
You're talking about a 7% print on
inflation.
Now, that is well above, of course, what
they've been targeting.
So certainly we'll see how this But
they're talking about food or energy
that really drove this this jump here as
well.
So lots to talk about, of course, as we
come out of the RBA decision as well.
They're set to hike for a third straight
meeting.
Yes.
In fact, Julie Chu will be joining us
out of HSBC to help us really
understand.
So you had the Philippine peso, you
know, where they think that's going to
go next.
The BSP needs to do more in terms of
intervention to really stem the losses
there.
She also has some really good thoughts
on the Japanese yen and whether or not
we should be on the lookout for further
intervention there.
And of course, the RBA, given just this
broad hawkish tilt we're seeing across
the world.
And just, you know, just one last note
in the Philippines too, right?
The last conversation we had with it
with the BSP governor, where the the
debate within the board was not so much
the height but the size of the hike.
At the last meeting they were thinking
of going even 50 at that point.
And might this print even bring a space
case and might they have to do something
even before that next meeting on June
18?
Anyway, lots to talk about with Joey Chu
coming up as well.
We will leave you with a look at the
Hang Seng tech index, which is down 2%
or effectively back to levels on Friday,
which really underscores sometimes why
it just pays not to do anything.
Right.
At some point, the sun will cross back
above you.
You just have to wait a full year.
But it's going to come back sooner or
later.
That's exactly where we are on Friday's
levels at the Hang Seng Tech Index.
Welcome back to the China Show.
A much different sort of picture that
we've seen from about 24 hours ago.
We were talking about Asian stocks at
records here.
Word out come off that just given the
latest when it comes to Iran, where you
have the U.S.
and Iran exchanging fire in the Gulf,
there's cracks in this cease fire and
there's a lot of lingering questions of
what happens in the Strait of Hormuz.
So oil is well back above 113 or so for
Brent futures here this morning.
You are now even seeing Taiwan flip into
negative territory.
There you go.
Hong Kong down one and a half percent,
Dave.
Yeah, some of the big winners yesterday.
And traders are simply unwinding some of
those longs that they went into
yesterday short covering, if you think
about it, in some cases.
So it is generally a bout of risk
aversion, although S&P futures are
finding a somewhat of a floor going into
the session today.
So one of note the other thing, of
course, is Philippine inflation, which
the equity market, by the way, is, I
believe, at session highs right now.
So climbing continuing to move against
the grain of what you would ever expect
to there.
The comment coming through out of
Bloomberg Economics is, yes, we will
likely get a hike and it's really a
question of how much the next hike will
be, how big the next hike will be.
It's June 18.
That I dare I say.
Should we now entertain even an off
cycle move, given how quickly, of
course, is inflation?
Print is effectively tripled from the
start of the year because of this energy
exposure that the economy has dollar
China dollar, Japan dollar parts.
And of course we also have an RBA
decision coming through today and the
expectation is for a hike, with the
exception, I believe, of one economist,
our very own, our very own.
MacIntyre So we will we will see if this
turns out to be the one.
Okay.
Oil prices, an update there.
I think we settled at 1.6 on West Texas,
114 and Brent, we're coming up a little
bit there gold is just at about has been
extremely rangebound but it's been at
the very low end of that range of 4500
on on Brent featured on gold futures.
It was an interesting take from Mark
Franklin from Manulife about why we're
seeing gold behave that it is is because
there's a lot of central banks right now
that need the dollar is reality.
And what they're doing is they're
selling gold to try to source that
dollars as a source for energy
alternatives around the world.
So certainly that's one thing to watch
as well.
But yes, when it comes to oil, once
again, we're coming off the highs, but
we're still talking about a bit of a
wake up call here this morning.
The U.S.
and Iran have exchanged fire in the
Persian Gulf and a flare up of violence
that also drew in the United Arab
Emirates.
For the latest is Bringing our Horizons
Middle East and Africa anchor Jomana
Barshefsky.
She joins us now from Dubai.
I just want to bring in below our China
correspondent.
She's here with us in the studio
tomorrow.
I'll start with you.
What really led to this latest flare up,
you think?
Yeah, well, you know, things have
dramatically taken a turn for the worse
in the last 24 hours.
And I think the main catalyst was the
fact that yesterday, around this time,
President Trump put up a post on social
announcing this project Freedom, and the
fact that the US were going to start not
escorting is the words that are used,
but guiding some of the stranded vessels
that were stuck in the Persian Gulf
through the Strait of Hormuz and i.e.
just physically forcing their way
through the Strait of Hormuz in a
flagrant violation of the Iranian
blockades, i.e.
their patience with the Iranian blockade
had started to run thin.
And so that set off a series of events
yesterday.
It was a very active day on the straits.
Loads of signals being
triggered.
We had multiple reports of vessels being
attempted to get fired on the by the end
of the day.
CENTCOM said that two four, two US
flagged vessels did actually make it
through the Straits, but that they had
managed to successfully sort of
go past the threat of Iranian drones and
strikes.
There were attempted strikes on these US
vessels and then President Trump later
said that they had to specifically
target six of these very fast powered
Iranian boats.
A lot of activity on the streets.
And then at the same time the Iranians
had targeted and adnoc linked vessels.
So this was obviously UAE, a UAE flagged
vessel off the coast of Fujairah.
And then later on in the evening, UAE
residents started getting all of these
missile alerts, warnings, the first time
we've received them since the beginning
of the cease fire to indicate that there
was more incoming projectiles being
directed towards the UAE again, and
another flagrant violation of the cease
fire.
So the question where we go from here,
obviously, is there has been a lot of
activity on the streets, as I've been
talking about.
But at the same time, given that Iran
has started firing projectiles once
again at the UAE, not only how is the
UAE going to respond to that?
And they, of course, have massively
condemned these attacks and have
reiterated their right to self-defense.
But what did the US do here?
What is Israel do here?
An IDF official was quoted as saying
that they are ready to go once again.
And I think from this point onwards
President Trump has to make a decision
once again about whether we go back to a
full blown military escalation,
including on land, or whether we
continue with this battle of the
streets, so to speak,
about an hour and a half back.
Jomana, CV's reporting here that I think
to your point that you had two US Navy
destroyers transiting through the Strait
of Hormuz.
Where are we on the peace talks?
Are they still talking to each other?
Are we putting that on the backburner
for now, given everything that's taking
place in the last few hours?
Yes.
So I think here you need to think about
the sequencing.
Right.
And what the Iranians have said is in
order for them to move to the second
round of negotiations, they you need to
first have a mutual lifting of both
blockades around the Strait of Hormuz.
From President Trump standpoint, he's
always asserted that you can't separate
the two issues.
It's not as though, you know, Iran can
use this point of leverage so that they
can extract more concessions on the
nuclear file.
That is not acceptable to the US and is
the reason why they put this blockade in
in the first place.
It was not an ends in itself, but a
means to an end to extract more
concessions out of the Iranians.
So where we are today, it seems very
clear that the US wants to establish
safe pathways through the Strait of
Hormuz for commercial vessels and for
the vessels that are stranded there.
Yesterday we heard from the the the head
of the Central Command, Admiral Cooper,
and he was saying that the there are
mines on the strait, but it's not
extensive and that for the US they
actually can establish these safe
pathways.
And yesterday was a bit of a test as we
were talking about because of those two
vessels that managed to navigate through
safely.
Of course, the Iranians have a different
take on it.
And you were just putting up a post
there from the Iranian foreign minister,
Abbas Araqchi, and he said this is a
political conflict and it can't be
solved militarily.
Any any action on the Strait of Hormuz
will prompt a retaliation out of the
Iranians.
And so from their perspective, it seems
as though their inkling or moving
towards wanting to restart those
diplomatic discussions again.
But the from the US perspective, their
patience has run thin with what the
Iranians have been doing around the
Strait of Hormuz, hence the action in
the last 24 hours.
Yeah, and you talk about the diplomacy
in the previous hour here.
We did hear from President Trump and he
still seems confident he's going to be
meeting with President Xi this month.
Let's take a listen.
First, we're leading China in a and I'm
going to go see presidency in two weeks.
I look forward to that.
But I'll say I'm.
We have
we have friendly we have very friendly
competition.
But it'll be a actually, it'll be a very
important trip.
It's going to happen, it seems.
But how is it going to change the whole
dynamics with this Iran situation?
Yeah, I think it's interesting.
He made a comment, almost a joke there
about how the US is leading and is
coming against this backdrop where
people are starting to question whether
the US is entering this summit in a
weakened position.
Just because the Iran war is so dragging
on.
The cease fire is quite fragile here and
yet the US has not announced or
declared.
Has been broken.
Clearly the US still trying to keep
things on the rail here.
Whether or not it's going to change
things is in Iran.
I think China's position on Iran has
been nothing but consistent.
And despite the latest calls from Scott
Bessant for China to participate in this
mission, in that project, freedom to try
to escort these ships out of the Strait
of Hormuz, we haven't heard from China,
but so far signals from China are that
they don't want to commit anything
militarily by sending naval assets to
the region to escort the ships.
They would see this as a form of action
that could provoke escalation from Iran,
particularly as Iran had made specific
threats on US ships that are approaching
the strait and again, explicitly calling
ships that are passing through to seek
permission from Iran.
Just dawned on me that meeting is ten
days away and any expectation that the
war would be over by the time these to
meet?
I think it's we could we could toss it
out the window.
What did we talk about?
This soybeans very quickly because the
market has turned their attention out of
soybeans yet again.
Yeah.
So if you look at what the markets are
pricing when it comes to soybean
futures, that is at the highest level in
near term since mid-March, which means
that traders are expecting that perhaps
or at least they are hoping that China
would purchase more soybeans from the
US.
And this is something we are watching
because remember the last time that they
met when President Trump, as he met in
South Korea, China actually had bought
some soybeans ahead of the summit as a
goodwill measure.
Will they do it this time?
That window is closing.
We are less than ten days away.
We haven't seen that sort of gesture
yet.
And of course, traders are hoping that
China would buy more old US soybeans in
the coming summer months.
Typically, China doesn't like to do
that.
They like to buy it at the end of the
year when when the new crops come out,
because in the summer months, Brazilian
soybeans tend to be cheaper.
So again, there are no signals from both
the US and Chinese side that that is
going to happen.
But certainly traders are speculating
that maybe that could be at least a a
low hanging fruit that could come out of
this summit.
All right, Tim, thank you so much.
Min Menlo there on the China angle.
And Jomana, of course, Pachachi there in
Dubai for us with all the latest coming
throughout the region coming up.
HSBC, head of Asia Research, Ethics
Research, specifically, Joey Chu, will
be joining us to talk us through, well,
basically their take on everything
that's been going on in the ethics
markets, everything from yen
intervention.
We had this RBA decision.
It looks like they'll hike and this
really extremely hot, red hot inflation
print coming through the Philippines
will be joining us in a couple of
minutes.
Stay tuned for that conversation.
Lots more ahead.
This is the China show.
Right?
Yeah.
The currency markets, I think the market
has been extremely clear and swift from
almost from the get go, which currencies
just have been just are inherently
negative correlated to high oil prices.
Right.
And I think the the anchor that the yuan
brings is quite evident really from spot
returns since the war started.
And you have the big energy importers
like the Philippines, Thailand and India
have just really been bottom of the
barrel here.
And, you know, does this continue to be
the case three months in with oil at,
let's call it an average of 100 bucks
over the last three months or so, ten
weeks.
Let's bring in Joey Chu, head of Asia
ethics Research at HSBC.
Joey, good morning.
We were going I was going to ask you
about the yen, but this inflation came
out of the Philippines today is forcing
my hand.
Do you think that this should be
consider a 50 basis point hike now
from the BSP and should be able to
continue
to be active in the markets?
Look, I think in the Philippines,
inflation is definitely rising a lot
above expectations.
There might be a lot of this second
round effects that's already happening,
for example, in food, etc..
So so yeah, I think BSP will clearly be
and still be very concerned.
And you know, more rate hikes definitely
is likely on the cards.
There's also HSBC economist base case as
well, whether you will help the peso or
not.
I think, you know, it's subject to how
oil prices are doing still and how risk
sentiment will hold up.
And also for Philippines, a lot of this
is inevitable, right?
Do with the current account deficit.
It takes time to correct that.
Yeah.
I mean, as you saw in that chart there,
the bottom, the barrel in terms of
Asia's worst performing currencies since
this war began, how are you assessing
the sensitivities of these currencies in
Asia to the oil price right now, which
are particular, you know, beyond the
Philippines, the most exposed and most
vulnerable right now?
I think Thai baht is also I mean, it is
the second worst performing currency for
good reason.
Right.
But the good thing about Thai baht
compared to Pessoal is that inflation is
starting at a lower point.
Right.
So, you know, the pain to the economy
seems to be a little bit more delayed or
a little bit less.
But that being said, there are other
issues for Thai baht, right?
For example, the fact is that Thai baht
or Thailand, the economy's actually very
exposed to the economies in Middle East.
So as the Middle East economies get into
a worse and worse shape and there will
be other spillover effects into the Thai
economy as well.
For example, tourism.
Yeah,
go ahead.
Go ahead.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Jovial tourism so so clearly that the
bat and the parcel remain the case.
I wonder whether this is this is it.
In other words, you know, the market, as
we were pointing out and as you know,
has been extremely quick to
to to toss the the currencies into
respective barrels, you know, the
inherently bad and inherently just
fundamentally okay.
But with oil prices, let's call it three
months now at 100 bucks, is this going
to show up in another way in currency
markets that we should start to, I
guess, expect?
I mean, look, I think as oil prices stay
high for longer and longer.
Even those that have inventory
stockpiles, eventually they will also
run into some issues that they would not
have.
If, you know, if the issue if the whole
conflict had just ended in one or two
months.
So I think we need to be careful here
about, you know, who are the ones that
are truly resilient.
I mean, I think even resilience has to
be relative within the within the Asian
context and not necessarily against the
dollar.
And we've seen, you know, the
intervention or what we can gather as
what looks to be intervention even from
the Japanese last week.
Right.
Where were you know, it seemed like 160
was a clear line in the sand and they
finally acted out in some ways where,
you know, we're sub 160 now.
You know, how much intervention can can
Japan do and can they actually keep him
below 60?
I mean, we had, you know, one a few days
of intervention potentially, as you know
here.
Japan has a lot of effects.
Me says I don't think the issue here is
about reserves adequacy.
It's not about the means, whether they
have enough means to do it.
It's about whether the efficacy, you
know, like whether it is a good timing
to do it right now when oil prices are
still rising.
I mean, obviously they want to do it
with speculative forces a lot.
But right now, I think they're slowly
cleaning up speculative positions
already.
So we might need to wait for another
build up, I think, before we see another
round of intervention.
And, you know, for investors and traders
out there, Joey, that obviously continue
to expect and I imagine based on your
comment there, also expect the yen to
continue to be weak.
How do you now express that, though, now
that it seems like on dollar yen
specifically, we have a very strong line
of descent, albeit, of course, maybe
transitory.
Yeah, that's right.
I mean, millions are always going to be
subject to a lot of intervention risk.
But, you know, even before dollar yen
was, you know, moving a lot, actually
the yen near the yen against a basket of
currencies was already hitting record
lows for quite a few weeks even before
this round of intervention.
So as I mentioned, I think the yen is
just weak from a lot of reasons.
B, from the risk appetite reasons or
from the U.
Differential or from oil imports.
So I think there are other ways to
express this other than just against the
dollar.
Yeah, it it seems interesting too, with
the dollar, right?
I mean, what we heard from the Fed last
week was that, you know, they were less
less dovish and it seems like it's got
to be higher for longer, at least well
into 2027, it seems.
You know, what we're seeing in the the
pricing, I mean, is this going to be a
substantial shift where it reinforces a
more structural support for the dollar
moving forward?
Yeah, I think so, because previously I
think though the thing that was holding
the bag was this idea that, you know,
the Trump administration somehow wants a
weaker dollar and might potentially be
able to get it maybe through, you know,
a new governor.
But as it turns out, you know, the shift
is happening in the FOMC already and the
data is panning out to be quite
supportive of a strong dollar.
So it's possible that as long as oil
prices stay high, the dollar might not
be able to sell off that easily.
Of course, we can still see from this
positioning and from, you know, whenever
there is some kind of positive headline
coming out from the conflict, there's a
lot of a sell, a dollar trade.
I think that will still be in play.
And for us, you know, I think a
de-escalation type of trade will
inevitably have to be something like a
sell dollar trade.
Yet, Joey, we're not even
mid-May, not even midway point of the
year.
I have actually had it just with news
flow.
It's just been extremely crazy.
I'm sure you guys, to just following
these headlines.
If I want to fall asleep today and buy a
bond, buy a currency and wake up this
time next year.
Joey, what is that trade?
Yeah,
look, I think it's for us.
We in Asia, we still like R&B,
especially on a relative value basis.
I mean, I think even against the dollar
is quite stable, it is likely to still
appreciate against a lot of other Asian
currencies.
We also like it against the euro and
other currency that I also think will
hold up reasonably well.
This the same dollar.
Admittedly, both R&B and sing dollar are
relatively low yielding but you know you
that's that's the trade off right the
safety and the resilience there is
something has to give.
Yeah we'll take that.
Yeah.
Boringness at any anyway give me that
near.
All right, Joey, thanks for joining us
there.
Do you their head of research at HSBC
joining us from Singapore.
Also ahead, look now to what's expected
to be a third straight hike from the RBA
today, unwinding all of last year's
cuts, of course, because of the Iran
war, the inflation risk out there.
We've got a preview coming up.
Perhaps a bit of a non consensus call
from our aboubakar nomics.
This is Bloomberg.
So stories that we're following for you
today, Palantir Technologies has raised
its revenue outlook for the year to
almost $7.7 billion.
That's far exceeding analysts estimates.
Sales in the first quarter rose to a
record 1.63 billion.
For us, commercial sales fell short of
expectations.
Palantir's long running deals with the
U.S.
and foreign governments now faces
growing competition from rival tech
companies.
The SEC says it's investigating
allegations of fraud in a U.S.
private credit firms.
And Chairman Paul Atkins told the Milken
Conference in Beverly Hills they're
taking the allegation seriously, but
declined to say specifically which
companies are under scrutiny.
Atkins has previously said the sector is
not a systemic risk, but noted in April,
the commission was tracking, quote,
emerging pressures.
A Hong Kong insider trading trial has
been told that Bank of America staff
working on a 2017 share sale did not
Wall Cross exotic capital management
before disclosing some information about
the potential deal.
Prosecutors made the claim A second
founder, Simon Sadler, and former trader
Daniel LaRocca, face court.
They pleaded not guilty to insider
dealing over a 2017 block trade of
shares in fashion company Esprit.
Tick Tock owners Bytedance says it will
be charging some users for its AI chat
bot double with fees ranging from 0 a
month for the basic version to more than
$70 more sophisticated platforms.
But it has not said when those plans
will go into effect.
By then, says Doble will continue to
offer a free version for, quote, daily
needs.
Okay.
10% gains on media tech listed in
Taiwan.
This is a really interesting story.
Daily limits.
Second straight day.
I think we had similar gains that we had
on Monday here.
So obviously better than expected set of
numbers coming out of the company.
Have upbeat guidance as well.
Really one of the best performing stocks
across the region today.
Granted, of course, it's a smaller pool
because a lot of markets are shots,
Right.
There's a trading debut to tell you
about here in Hong Kong.
Star sports medicine.
We are coming off highs.
We opened about 190 or so percent to the
upside for paring some of that right
now.
But, yes, again, another blockbuster
debut here in Hong Kong earnings.
HSBC is coming out in about 90 minutes
or so.
So watch out for things like
Jaws, which is effectively
profitability.
It's interesting, too, on a really good
point coming through out of Denise, We
are finance reporter who joined us
earlier with a preview and look out if
they will do a stanchart if they will
provision more in terms of their
exposure on the loan book because of
their massive presence, of course, in
the Middle east.
Stanchart did I think, roughly the same.
But on the wealth side and on the market
side of things, things are actually
quite well When you look at the other
Wall Street, other banks that have
reported it.
Yeah, so certainly that's one thing.
There was also news of ICBC re acquiring
HSBC, Indonesia, retail and wealth
assets as well that came out here early
this morning as well.
So that's one they don't deal with here
when it comes to HSBC.
And of course, as we remind you, Chinese
markets, you have Japan and Korea.
Those three are all shut today.
So certainly that does lead to some
volumes a bit lower here.
You know, risk sentiment is low.
You know, there is a lot, you know,
hanging here.
I'm really what what what looks what do
we look where we go from here after you
see this whole Iraq situation reignite
once again, I think prolonged conflict
is the assumption coming throughout the
Bloomberg economic sporadic fighting to
get used to that.
And oil will remain on on the elevated
side of things.
Just a note on the volumes that Yvonne
just mentioned.
There were about 90% lighter on the
benchmark basis.
So it really goes to show what are we
even doing here?
There's lots of things going on.
All right.
We'll take a short break.
We'll be back on the other side of it.
All right.
We are checking when it comes to ozone
assets here today, that RV decision in
just about, well, 2 hours or so.
And certainly we talked about, you know,
the effects express has been really big
when it comes to energy prices.
And what we've been seeing in really
Asia affects Aussie dollar, though,
stands out on a good note.
It's one of the ones that actually has
been gaining all this year.
Obviously, we've been talking about when
it comes to rate hikes.
Right.
They are set to deliver a third straight
rate hike later on today.
But yeah, I think all but one economists
thinks that they will do that today.
Yeah, if only we had access to that one.
That one, that lone one.
What is happening underneath the hood.
In fact you know we actually do see up
31 out of 32 Think they'll hike.
That one, of course, joins us right now.
James MacIntyre, our Bloomberg
economist, of course thinks that the RBA
that if the RBA hikes it, it would be a
a policy mistake.
JAMES Yeah.
Good morning.
Lay out the case for us.
Why?
Why would it be erroneous to move today?
Yeah.
When you're thinking about monetary
policy, you know, interest rate
movements operate with long and variable
lags, right?
And so any move today by the central
bank, whether it's the RBA or anyone,
there's a strong chance that as the
growth hit percolates its way through
the global economy and it's going to hit
Australia's economy fairly substantially
over coming months, as that growth hit
arrives, it's going to quash these
inflation pressures and see central
banks potentially having to reverse
course.
So if you, you know, by definition, if
you if you're hiking rates and then
having to quickly go back in the other
direction, it's kind of an indication
that that might have been a policy
mistake.
We don't know is the challenge.
And that's a very significant
uncertainty to the environment and a
very significant uncertainty for policy
making for the.
And so my view is with the RBA having
raised rates twice already this year,
February, March, back to back rate
hikes, it's for them to deliver a third
hike when we've got an inflation outcome
that's backward looking.
That was okay and some wobbly economic
numbers.
It might just be that they're lining up
for a very quick reversal of any rate
hikes that they might deliver this
afternoon.
But I'm still talking about oil markets
that are north of 100, 110.
Even if you look at some contracts and
there's no sign of this war really
ending any time soon.
Do you think the RBA has done enough in
terms of taming inflation expectations?
Well, what's really.
Yeah, that's right.
Are those two hikes that they've
delivered thus far enough to put the to
keep the inflation genie a little bit
restrained?
Because we know that no matter what the
RBA or any central bank does is no
amount of interest rate hikes that are
going to reopen the Strait of Hormuz.
But what has been also done in the
background in the Australian context
that's very important and interesting
for inflation from an inflation
expectations perspective, is the work
that the Government has been doing on
the side.
There's a big move by the government to
reduce fuel taxes and also efforts to
secure throughout from Asian refiners,
secure domestic fuel supplies and put a
price on those.
And so what's happened is that we've
actually seen in the weekly data that
came out yesterday and we put this in
the in the note that we did previewing
the RBA, we saw that those petrol prices
at the pump are back to where they were
at pre-war levels, despite the Brent and
wholesale crude prices being what they
are.
That's a very significant effort when it
comes to those tax cuts and a lot of
heavy lifting by the government that
will result in consumers inflation
expectations being pulled back down.
That's a big help for the RBA.
James, let's maybe let's go down the the
slow down route that you the premise and
your thesis here.
And if I could ask my producers to pull
up the can we pull up the cash rate
chart again because say if they hike
today they'll take the cash rate back
effectively to the peak of the cycle
which and you know, effectively they,
they didn't cut rates anyway even
halfway back down.
So effectively the last, what, three,
four years rates have been extremely
high and restrictive.
Well, number one, do you agree with that
assessment that they have been
restrictive enough?
And why hasn't the economy responded to
such tight policy?
Well, part of the what's going on and
what's helpful for Australia's economy
is the population story.
So we've got a less buoyant environment,
I guess, offshore.
And so Australians are staying at home
instead of leaving.
And so that net inbound migration that
we have has resulted in strong
population growth, which has been a bit
of a growth boost or growth driver, a
recession.
New Zealand is actually a bit of a
problem for the Reserve Bank of
Australia because Kiwis are allowed to
move freely and so that's added labour
supply, but it's also added demand in
the economy.
So that's one of the things that
monetary policy in Australia is actually
needed to be a little bit tight for.
So it hasn't held back growth that much
because we've had extra people coming in
per capita growth.
That's actually where you do see when
you pull apart the economy, you do see
that weakness coming through.
And that per capita growth is likely to
be weaker going forward based on what
consumers are telling us.
High frequency consumer sentiment
indicators and the monthly ones are
telling us that consumers are feeling
very, very scared about this, very
uncertain, and they have very
significant fears about their
unemployment and their jobs.
And that's something that we think aside
from the petrol prices which have
returned the energy hit, potentially
soaking up some of the cash in their
wallets, But those wallets staying
closed, and that's a big challenge when
it comes to demand, and that's the type
of growth it that will increasingly
become apparent as over the course of
the rest of this year.
And that could be the thing that results
in the RBA having to turn around,
perhaps even as soon as the end of next
year or we think early end of this year,
or we think what's more likely is early
in 2027 is when they begin to cut
jobs.
James, very interesting take there.
Thanks so much for giving us the other
side of that perspective of really what
everyone is saying is going to be the
case for a whole.
James MacIntyre, our Bloomberg economist
there, joining us out of Sydney.
And of course, survivors can also turn
to your terminal for more of this
upcoming RBA decision.
T live go is up and running in your
function for the latest updates was
commentary and analysis from our expert
editors.
A stay on when it comes to Australia now
because Westpac says that geopolitical
conflict is forcing new scenario
modeling of oil supply shocks and price
risks.
The bank's chief economist, Lucy Ellis,
spoke to us at the Bloomberg New Voices
event in Sydney alongside ten CAP
co-founder Jim Ballou.
And Goldman Sachs is head of Australia
and M&A.
Marissa, a friend.
The way we tend to frame it is twofold.
One is holding on to kind of core
principles rather than specific
relationships.
So you're thinking through will people
will respond to this.
So that's one you've always got to go
beyond your first round thinking people
will respond.
So high oil prices, well, people will
buy electric cars.
People will try and find other places
where they can produce oil.
People will stop lying.
So much on the US for defense
partnership.
So you've got to think about how will
the other person react.
And that really helps you think through
things.
The second thing that we've done, and
this is something we've done quite a bit
recently at Westpac, economics is making
greater use of scenarios, so we're
always publishing forecasts.
So we have a monthly forecast
publication.
But increasingly we are using scenarios
to articulate the risks in a different
way.
Now that does require having sort of
more sophisticated modelling than than
typically our customers.
We're used to saying.
And so there's a lot of that going on
behind the scenes.
It's something we probably couldn't have
done a few years ago is easily, but we
think it's important to be transparent
about where some of those uncertainties
are.
And so you'll see the for the
forecasting scenarios we've published
based on, okay, if the Strait of Hormuz
is closed for this long, how does that
change your assumptions about overall
global supply?
Based on what we know about demand for
oil and how people respond to higher
prices, what does that mean for the
market clearing price?
We're not just making up a price.
We are actually modelling that from the
underlying demand and supply.
And so to be able to do that and go down
to the next layer of abstraction is
really important.
Jim But you thrive on volatility, right?
We love it.
We're in the equity market.
Look,
what equity market is trying to do is
that we combine what economists think
and what's happening with the economy
and trying to predict what happens in 6
to 12 month time.
So that's why you see the volatility is
because the view is 6 to 12 month time
keeps changing.
Now, of course, that's also because fund
managers also think we know a lot better
than everyone else.
So we know a little bit of something.
And but look, look for in 12 month, we
keep thinking, okay, what does that
mean?
Has I changed how I think about in 12
month time?
Now, Australia had an inflation problem
before we even start this war, so that
inflation problem is still going to be
intact.
So, you know, RBA is going to put up
their interest rate, They will continue
to put up the interest rate even without
worrying about these wars.
So these are some of the things that we
can anchor on to.
So as an equity market investor, we
still think okay, areas that gets
impacted by high interest rate will
still get impacted, other areas will
still be going along their path.
Now war just made it worse, so it's made
a worse.
And you know, potentially there'll be
more lingering impacts.
Consumer make it impacted a little bit
more.
So there's a whole lot of things now
that that's why you see a little bit
more volatility in those share prices
Now No, as a fundamental investor, this
is actually where you see opportunity.
You're absolutely right, particularly
where you can go long and short.
It's a bit tougher in your space, isn't
it, Marissa, How do you determine
fundamental value at a time when markets
are so volatile?
The market that I operate in has just
said, well, perhaps we live in a
volatile world and perhaps that volatile
world is going to persist for a while
and we can't stop, you know, running our
businesses.
We can't stop doing things that makes
you tragic sense.
So let's just keep going,
notwithstanding that environment so that
there are some green shoots that we're
starting to see.
Yeah,
there we go, Heidi, of course, and her
fantastic panel there in Sydney at the
joining us, of course, at the Bloomberg
Voices event taking place there very,
very recently.
Right.
Just ahead, Indian Prime Minister
Narendra modi winning big in state
elections with voters taking two of his
most outspoken opponents.
We'll have the details next.
This is Bloomberg.
Let's turn our attention now to India,
where you have the prime Minister,
Narendra modi's BJP has expanded its
support base in state elections with
voters ousting two of the opposition's
most vocal leaders in the process.
April Hong is with us right now with the
details of the results.
And I think more importantly about what
this actually could mean
for Modi.
Yeah, this is significant for him.
I mean, just coming two years after he
was dealt a blow at the national
elections by not winning a majority this
time around, he's managed to show his
enduring popularity with the BJP's
resounding victory in the eastern state
of West Bengal and then, of course, in
Tamil Nadu with a shock loss for the
incumbent.
Then essentially what Modi's managed to
do now is take out to very vocal
opposition critics.
For example, you look at West Bengal,
where Mamata Banerjee was a stalwart.
She is, of course, India's most high
profile female politician and also seen
as somebody that was the most a possibly
mounting a credible opposition to Modi
in the 29 national elections.
And think about as well with the victory
of sorts for Joseph Vijay in Tamil Nadu,
which of course is a state that is an
economic powerhouse, this essentially
seen as allowing Modi's allies to align
more closely with him.
So all in all, is seen as Modi being
able to gain fresh momentum to pursue
his economic his political agenda.
And this coming at a time when obviously
Indian stocks are sort of out of favor.
What do you think the market reaction is
going to be like?
Yeah, they've come under a lot of
pressure.
Obviously, India as a market, as you
know, it has one of the highest negative
correlations in the region to the oil
prices.
And we are seeing the futures coming out
of Persia.
No thanks to the recent rebound.
So call it a case of bad timing.
But actually last night we did see
already some of the early reaction to
the election results, that victory
optimism, so to speak.
And of course, this was also part of the
broader rally we saw in the region,
which was led by tech.
Now, among the market reaction, specific
sectors that we are watching will be the
Adani group of companies, given how they
have been aligning very closely with
Modi's agenda.
We're also watching industrial
infrastructure related stocks.
They might benefit a little bit, even
though on an index level we might still
see India coming under pressure.
I would just note as well that
renewables, those are a bunch of stocks
that have really rallied very hot so far
this year amid the push for them, some
of them climbing by double digits so far
this year.
So we're watching that in terms of the
reaction going into the markets open
today.
All right, April, thank you.
April Hong there with a preview of what
to expect when it comes to Indian
markets as they open up to this new
election.
Is that a boost for Modi and the BJP
party?
And you stay on what really has been
going on, Right.
This equities rebound that we've seen in
India has witnessed in bonds gathering
pace in the coming months.
And it's not really the foreign investor
side of things that's really playing
ball here.
It's really the local domestic flows
that are supporting this market still
and they're still looking ahead when it
comes to earnings and they say could be
pretty rosy, too, so far.
Yeah, I think the statistic that we
looked at here was I think whenever the
index gained 5% in a month, it tended to
continue those gains, about 80, you
know, they say 84, 85% at the time.
Yeah.
Moving forward.
And I think in this case, the premise is
that local investors will fill the shoes
of because you know, foreign investors
and it's not just solely in India.
Right.
You look at other end markets, you look
at some benchmarks in China, foreign
dollar, investors have their eyes set
on,
you know, sort of the shiny cities on
the Hill.
Right.
Like like Korea, like Taiwan.
But I just my counter take here is that
for for this market to pick up you kind
of have to take the air is somewhat
needs to go away right because some of
the big software place
Infosys TCS are down 25% year to date.
So for this market to turn around that
thesis, someone has to get sort of eaten
up a little bit and it's very difficult
to see how that quickly could it can
both co-exist.
Certainly can.
But yeah,
okay.
So there's that certainly here.
Valuations are still not cheap, right?
You're still talking about 40% premium
for India over its emerging peers in
Asia.
We do have this breaking news.
The interesting scoop here that we're
seeing when it comes to Apple as well.
So what we are hearing here right now is
Apple exploring using Intel as well as
Samsung to build device processors here.
So this is what we're hearing so far.
They're doing expirations with those two
companies, Intel and Samsung.
They remain preliminary at this point.
They still see challenges when it comes
to Intel and Samsung catching up to the
likes of TSMC here right now.
But they are still talking with the
likes of those two companies.
But at this point, they're still saying
it may not lead to an agreement.
But yes, this is what they're at least
exploring here right now, according to
our team at B and then the sources that
they're speaking to.
Yeah.
And could come at the expense
potentially of this moves at the expense
of longtime partner at TSMC.
Of course, in terms of just being able
to broaden out their exposure across
that across that supply chain.
Yes.
And everyone is pointing out all the big
companies here involve Apple, Intel,
Samsung and TSMC have had declined
comment.
But I think just looking at market
reaction at TSMC, I guess for the
initial data, it's also worth pointing
out, of course, we were already on a
sort of done trajectory on TSMC and I
think there is a Samsung ETF here in
Hong Kong which I think we can get to
later on.
But yes, that is the breaking scoop
coming through here.
Right.
We have lots more in the way here on the
China show.
Plenty more ahead.
This is Bloomberg.
All right.
Just recapping that Bloomberg scoop that
just came through at your Bloomberg
terminal here.
So Apple is now holding discussions with
the likes of Intel, as well as Samsung
to build device processors.
So this is just a secondary option
beyond just what their partnership with
TSMC here right now.
But they are looking at possibly talking
to these two companies here.
But at the talk at this stage as we know
it, are preliminary right now.
Yes.
And this seems to be just looking at
some of the details here to broaden out
beyond the longtime partner, maybe
supply chain exposure.
The longtime partner, of course, is
TSMC.
And we understand, of course, that we
have reached out to the companies
involved and they have declined to
comment on this.
On your screens, any market reaction?
I can tell you right now, S&P futures,
at least here, have been trading in and
around these levels for the better part
of the last few hours or so.
Let's why don't we bring in Mark Gurman,
of course, who is has spearheaded this
this this Bloomberg scoop for us to give
us more details and context.
Mark, again, fantastic set of reporting,
sir, what more can you tell us about
this?
Yes.
So obviously, Apple is facing some
supply chain shortages right now related
to chips.
Why?
Because their Macs are in extremely high
demand because they're one of the best
platforms for running on device models.
The other thing you're facing here is
the entire industry meeting additional
demand because everyone wants to run air
models.
Now people are buying computers for it.
And so you've seen shortages to the Mac
Mini, you've seen shortages.
The Mac studio, Tim Cook talked about it
on the Apple earnings call last week.
He believes these shortages are going to
last several months, but Apple has been
looking for secondary suppliers for TSMC
for well over a year now TSMC is at the
forefront.
They are far and away the best
technology provider for the advanced
nodes for manufacturing.
But you need if you're Apple, given your
volumes, secondary suppliers, they have
it for displays, they have it for pretty
much everything else they can.
And so they are exploring and looking
into the idea of having backup
suppliers.
TSMC in the top of the list is Intel and
Samsung Intel, because now they're part
of the the US government and that would
be solid relations and it's a good
comeback story for a U.S.
firm in Samsung.
You know they're the second in terms of
top tier foundries around the world and
they're building new advanced node
plants in the U.S.
as well.
Talk to us about
the I mean, obviously, we understand the
need to be more flexible on their supply
chains,
but are there concern I mean, how
serious are they looking at other
companies right now, given that, you
know, TSMC has been that dominant, made
to order chip manufacture for them for
so long now?
Are there concerns that they have about
using non TSMC technology?
Nothing is imminent.
I don't expect 90% SI chips to go into
Apple products anytime soon.
But given Apple's volumes and the
reliance that so many people have on
Apple, it would be only responsible for
them to be taking a close look at
alternative providers.
So that's exactly what they're doing.
But I don't expect anything imminent at
this point.
Martin Thank you.
Mark Gurman There are of course there
are out of him and the team that you can
check that out, of course, on your
Bloomberg.
Nothing is imminent.
And as far as that decision is
concerned, the fact that they are
thinking about considering broadening
that supply chain from TSMC.
Speaking of TSMC, let's
tell you an airport here, of course, in
Taiwan.
Yeah, it almost kind of weaves into it
perfectly where the president lighting
has arrived at Telluride Airport here in
the last couple of minutes and making
that speech to reporters at the airport.
This, of course, after defying China to
visit his surprise trip to as Watney.
Right.
And this was despite what we heard from
reports about Beijing's efforts to
really try to thwart his diplomatic
outreach.
And so it would be interesting to hear
what he has to say in this speech.
For one thing, you know, they've kept it
pretty mum when he left on when he was
returning and how long he was going to
be in as Watney and really how he got
back as well.
There was reports, according to our
sources, that he had used it as
Eswatini's private jet in terms of the
monarchy there.
So maybe we'll see how the motive is,
what he did to come back and how
difficult journey it might have been for
him.
But yeah, certainly going to be taking a
lot of questions there.
And tell you Antalya today, Dave
absolutely said we believe he has just
started speaking.
Of course, coming out of that hour, that
plane sweep.
It's worth pointing out that he has, at
least based on the headlines that have
yet to cross, nothing still of of knots.
And of course, of course, this is still
early goings there in in Taipei right
now.
We'll keep an eye on the story, of
course, for you.
Before we wrap things up here, just a
glance at how we're doing the Hang Seng
index as we enter the last hour of the
morning session there.
Of course, it's extremely thin trading
given a lot of major markets are closed.
Mainland China, South Korea and Japan
are not trading today.
We're down about 1%.
That's it from us here on the China show
Insight with Haslinda Amin is coming up next.